<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writer. Nerd. Houseplant. on Michael Buckley</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writer. Nerd. Houseplant. on Michael Buckley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Just Now</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022.oct/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022.oct/</guid>
      <description>Writing with another person can be a wonderful experience. Turns out that’s even more true when you’re actually sitting beside your co-author. And not just because they smell nice. I’m writing with my fiancé so that last part isn’t weird.
So far most of the work on our novel has been done over the internet, over distance, and asynchronously—each working when our brains felt capable. And that hasn’t been hard. The majority of our relationship happens over long distance so we’re used to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The White Room With Black Curtains (By The Station)</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/whiteroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/whiteroom/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking a lot about scene description while attempting to write this book (yes that’s still happening). The question of how much scene setting is necessary? How much is enough? What’s too much? Too little? How many words are the difference between a scene that’s skeletal and one that’s chonky?
White Room Syndrome is the habit of creating a scenes that are so under-described, so lacking detail that it could be taking place in a featureless white-walled room in anywhere in the world1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words With Friend</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/friend/</guid>
      <description>It started with a tweet. Which became a discussion. Then became a plan. We would write a book together.
As you may know, this year my friend, Ciel, and I decided to attempt to write a novel together. Neither of us have written a novel before. And I haven’t co-written anything before. So we thought we should write some kind of work log in case we forget how we did this thing (or anyone ever asks about it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinning Worlds</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/spin/</guid>
      <description>I am a music guy. I am also a fan of physical media. And records—I cannot say &amp;lsquo;vinyl&amp;rsquo;—are the most physical of the physical media. They are big and heavy. They take up space. Because of this and a general lack of money my collection will always remain small, with just enough space for specific albums I know and love. I will list them here (the songs in italics are personal favs):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Hands</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/morehands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/morehands/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick update to the last post, which was somewhat technical. I promise to get to more writerly and fun topics soon
So the experiment failed. Sort of. Last time I talked about changing to vim in an effort to save my hands. Text entry of course ended up the same and I could keep hitting my (paltry) word counts. But when editing, well, there are too many commands to hold in my head, and most of my editing time was spent consulting the cheat sheet on my desk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/hands/</guid>
      <description>There are two things that became obvious while attempting NanoWriMo in 2020. First, that procrastination and global crisis are the most intimate of lovers and, second, my hands are no longer capable of typing at a computer like they once were.
As some of you may know, I have Muscular Dystrophy, which is a muscle weakening condition. What this means is, among myriad other things, my hands have been slowly worsening over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi I’m Michael.
I’m a writer and typo enthusiast from New South Wales, Australia.
Despite bad hands, my words have appeared in The Guardian and the Newcastle Short Story Anthology. More recently, I studied creative writing at the University of New England and completed an Advanced Diploma in Arts.
I’m mostly interested in disability, accessibility and technology, and the way these overlap with fiction and pop culture. I also like animation, Cormac McCarthy and Earl Grey tea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have any questions, comments, queries, inquiries, enquiries, refutations or rebuttals, please send me an email.
If you have anything particularly urgent or timely, twitter is best.
If you want to write me a letter, I really don’t know what to tell you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
