<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Michael Buckley</title>
        <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com</link>
        <description>Writer. Nerd. Houseplant.</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
            <title>Words with Friend</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/friend/</link>
            <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/friend/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It started with a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;phantomdiorama&#x2F;status&#x2F;1316232565515190273?s=20&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Which became a discussion. Then became a plan. We would write a book together. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, this year my friend, Ciel, and I decided to attempt to write a novel together. Neither of us have written a novel before. And I haven’t co-written anything before. So we thought we should write some kind of work log in case we forget how we did this thing (or anyone ever asks about it). Here goes...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very early on in our conversations we decided that I would do what we named a spaghetti draft—essentially the bones of the story—on my own before coming together to Make It Good. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that’s what I’ve been doing. I would write during the day and at night I’d slide into Ciel’s DMs with that day’s words, she’d say ‘Yes. Good.’ and we’d move on. We tried not to over–discuss this early work: mostly just what we liked (&lt;em&gt;‘Cat’ - Ciel&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;), what worked or didn’t, or which direction we should take (&lt;em&gt;‘More cat’ - Ciel&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). We talked mostly about big picture. The theme of the book. How the characters of the town would interact with each other. How to write a story where people are mostly nice to each other &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; how to make that interesting. About which pot plants would fit in a backpack. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gave ourselves (well, me) six months to complete this early draft. We finished on August 1st with around 31,000 words. Obviously, this is only the first step (and first blog post) of many. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is taking a deserved fortnight break and reading over our (actual physical sliced-tree) copies. Then comes the rubberducking&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now. You can follow our co-writerly adventures on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.twitter.com&#x2F;agapanthusfran&quot;&gt;@AgapanthusFran&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;‘This post needs more cat’ - Ciel&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Status&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cat: Languid&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing: Fermenting &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hands: In pocket &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“rubberducking” is a method of debugging code in which a programmer would carry around a rubber duck and debug their code by forcing themselves to explain it, line-by-line, to the duck. -- &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rubber_duck_debugging&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Spinning Worlds</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/spin/</link>
            <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/spin/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a music guy. I am also a fan of physical media. And records—I cannot say &#x27;vinyl&#x27;—are the most physical of the physical media. They are big and heavy. They take up space. Because of this and a general lack of money my collection will always remain small, with just enough space for specific albums I know and love. I will list them here (the songs in &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; are personal favs): &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;beth-gibbons-rustin-man-out-of-season&quot;&gt;Beth Gibbons &amp;amp; Rustin Man - Out Of Season&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first saw the video for Tom the Model on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rage_(TV_program)&quot;&gt;Rage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the early 2000s. Although it obviously sounded like Portishead, I didn’t make the connection until much later. &#x27;Tom&#x27; is the most Portishead-y track on the album though. The rest is folkier. With more daylight. Tinged with Nina Simone. &lt;em&gt;Mysteries, Funny Time Of Year.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Out_of_Season_(Beth_Gibbons_and_Rustin_Man_album)&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bob-dylan-oh-mercy&quot;&gt;Bob Dylan - Oh Mercy&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#x27;Most of the time I wouldn&#x27;t change it if I could.&#x27; I’m probably one of the few people that prefers Dylan’s later work—although it is a little brain-melty to think of an album from 1989 as late work. Personal nostalgia is difficult to pull off well and few can stand with Dylan, except maybe Leonard Cohen. Or Joni Mitchell. And even then, only at their best.  &lt;em&gt;Everything Is Broken, Most Of The Time.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Oh_Mercy&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;bob-dylan-rough-rowdy-ways&quot;&gt;Bob Dylan - Rough &amp;amp; Rowdy Ways&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An old American God recounts a disappearing century. A kind of public nostalgia. First Dylan album in ten years and maybe the only good to come out of Covid&#x27;s bad. &lt;em&gt;False Prophet, Murder Most Foul&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Rough_and_Rowdy_Ways&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;frank-sinatra-in-the-wee-small-hours&quot;&gt;Frank Sinatra - In The Wee Small Hours&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supposedly the very first &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Concept_album&quot;&gt;Concept album&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Reminds me of stumbling home from some fancy party, cotton-mouthed from cigarettes and whiskey, bowtie loose at my neck. OK that never happened. But the music is nice. Night-time distilled down and etched onto plastic. &lt;em&gt;Mood Indigo, I Get Along Without You Very Well.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;In_the_Wee_Small_Hours&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;massive-attack-mezzanine&quot;&gt;Massive Attack - Mezzanine&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably most famous for Teardrop—the video with baby singing in the womb. Which then became the theme for the show House. The building thrum of Angel is perhaps an all time album opener. Sadly, the album is somewhat top-heavy—the singles make up the first four songs, and while they are excellent, the second disc is less memorable. &lt;em&gt;Angel, Dissolved Girl.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Mezzanine_(album)&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nick-cave-idiot-prayer&quot;&gt;Nick Cave - Idiot Prayer&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK &lt;em&gt;this&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; may be the good to come out of Covid&#x27;s bad. Just Nick, a piano and a big empty room. Yes, it&#x27;s re-arrangements of old songs. Yet it&#x27;s a perfect companion for a world that aches as ours does now. &lt;em&gt;Nobody&#x27;s Baby Now, Brompton Oratory.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Idiot_Prayer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;pink-floyd-meddle&quot;&gt;Pink Floyd - Meddle&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Mason singing &#x27;one of these days I&#x27;m going to cut you into little pieces&#x27; sounds a Geiger–counter. And together with the driving bass-line makes for one of the most apocalyptic singles ever released. Side two’s calming Echoes has often been my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Pomodoro_Technique&quot;&gt;Pomodoro&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; timer. No-one needs to hear Seamus. &lt;em&gt;Fearless, Echoes.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Meddle&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;portishead-roseland-nyc&quot;&gt;Portishead - Roseland NYC&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If In The Wee Small Hours is the sound of a night done well, Roseland is a night gone askew. It’s a ballroom seen through the bottom of a glass. Basically a Best-Of. But with a warmth from the live strings. &lt;em&gt;All Mine, Over.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Roseland_NYC_Live&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>More Hands</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/morehands/</link>
            <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/morehands/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is just a quick update to the last post, which was somewhat technical. I promise to get to more writerly and fun topics soon&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the experiment failed. Sort of. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.michaelbuckleywriter.com&#x2F;hands&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Last time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I talked about changing to vim in an effort to save my hands. Text entry of course ended up the same and I could keep hitting my (paltry) word counts. But when editing, well, there are too many commands to hold in my head, and most of my editing time was spent consulting the cheat sheet on my desk. Editing became wading through sticky molasses. Had I stuck with it perhaps this need would lessen over time. Also, I kept falling back on using the mouse which is very much frowned on in vim circles. BUT it turns out my hands &lt;em&gt;require&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; the relief that comes with stopping and moving to the electric rodent. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not all wasted effort though. The separation of writing and editing into distinct contexts is something I plan to continue in future. And learning &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ziishaned&#x2F;learn-regex&quot;&gt;Regular Expressions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will be invaluable when doing a complicated search and replace task. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other parts of last month’s change-up have been more successful:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;phantomdiorama&#x2F;unsuckykeys&quot;&gt;unsucky keys&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the no-chording script I wrote is still in everyday use. There are bugs and edge-cases, but it works well and stable enough to stay out of the way &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing keyboards was the main positive this past month. The one I found in the drawer was a non-starter. Literally. The keys didn’t work. So, I purchased a Raspberry Pi keyboard and it’s become my daily driver. It’s sturdy for the price, has a USB hub, and the money goes to support the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.raspberrypi.org&#x2F;about&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I had to remap a couple keys to make my hands happy, but it has made a genuinely big difference to comfort and pains levels. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;pi keyboard&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Status&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cat: Reclining&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing: Optimistic&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hands: Cautious&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hands</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/hands/</link>
            <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/hands/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two things that became obvious while attempting &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nanowrimo.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;NanoWriMo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in 2020. First, that procrastination and global crisis are the most intimate of lovers and, second, my hands are no longer capable of typing at a computer like they once were.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, I have Muscular Dystrophy, which is a muscle weakening condition. What this means is, among myriad other things,  my hands have been slowly worsening over time. Think of how your hands look when holding a gamepad, now take the pad away and imagine you can’t straighten your fingers out. Yep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, I’ve gone from increasingly frequent typos—my twitter bio is now simply a warning of their presence—to actual pain. Sustained typing, and particularly chording, leads to cramping and pain in my fingers and across the knuckles. Because of this increasing pain, I had to ditch the computer partway through the first week of Nano and ended up tapping out the rest of the month’s word count on my phone. This had its own set of ergonomic problems. I got the 10,000 words I had planned. But something had to change. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;chords&quot;&gt;Chords&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing I looked into was alternative keyboard layouts. Perhaps there would be something more suitable to my circumstances than QWERTY. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.xkcd.com&#x2F;2007&#x2F;08&#x2F;14&#x2F;mirrorboard-a-one-handed-keyboard-layout-for-the-lazy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Mirror Layout&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; looked interesting but is built around chording &lt;code&gt;capslock&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; with your pinky: in fact, more chords with your worst finger. More well known alternative layouts like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;colemak.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Colemak&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dvorak_keyboard_layout&quot;&gt;Dvorak&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; focus on touch typing, which I can&#x27;t do, and spread keys more evenly across both hands. Dvorak does have a modified left–hand–only version supposedly designed for those with hand injuries. Unfortunately, none of these reduce the amount of chords. This, along with the cognitive load of learning a different layout, made this route a dead end. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stretching motion required to perform chords—especially those that include letters towards the centre of the keyboard—is the most fatiguing on my fingers so I want to avoid it as much as possible. Using the &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; key to pull up a menu and arrowing around is certainly doable but it’s slow and pushes me towards using the mouse. What I really want is what my phone does. Shifting on the iOS keyboard is a toggle. But not just a toggle, one that auto-offs. When you hit &lt;code&gt;shift&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; it toggles on and waits for the next input, capitalises it, and turns shift off. Turns out Windows has a version of this in the form of StickyKeys. I say &lt;em&gt;has&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in the sense that it’s a feature that exists. Unfortunately, I have never come across a more bug-riddled piece of software. What’s supposed to happen is StickyKeys turns the modifier keys (Alt, Control, Shift etc) into toggles so instead of pressing &lt;code&gt;control + x&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to paste you press  &lt;code&gt;control&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;em&gt;then&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;code&gt;x&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. And it does. Then it suddenly decides not to. Or it works two out of three times. Or after restarting, one out of seven. Or sometimes the process would just die. What I&#x27;m saying is it sucks. I&#x27;m not sure if this is specific to my setup or not, but after a couple of frustrating days wrestling with it I gave up and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;phantomdiorama&#x2F;unsuckykeys&quot;&gt;made my own&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It’s a quick and dirty script but it seems to serve my purposes. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;keyboard&quot;&gt;Keyboard&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current keyboard is a fat old Corsair mechanical. I’ve had it for years and I love it. But my fingers no longer do. So I&#x27;ve been looking into other mechanicals in smaller sizes and while both 60% and 40% models would occupy less space on my desk they are still pretty heavy and they make up for their lack of keys with either layers or functions, in other words more chords. Like with the keyboard layouts, the benefits they may bring over my current setup are most likely eroded by new negatives. For now I’ve decided to swap out the Corsair with a generic plastic ‘board I found in a drawer. It has flat chiclet laptop-style keys with a low travel distance. I&#x27;m hoping it will put less stress on my fingers. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;vim&quot;&gt;Vim&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While researching keyboard layouts and remapping I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stevelosh.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2012&#x2F;10&#x2F;a-modern-space-cadet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Modern Space Cadet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Steve Losh. In the post, Losh details how he went about creating a custom keymap. It’s long but well worth your time. And while Losh’s focus is programming, typing is typing and he has ideas there that I can steal. But the real reason I mention the post is because it acted, like many posts do, as a hypertext bread crumb trail and led to another of Losh’s posts on his &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stevelosh.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2010&#x2F;09&#x2F;coming-home-to-vim&#x2F;&quot;&gt;return to the text editor Vim&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had heard of Vim, of course, but I had written it off as too nerdy (yes, even for me), too esoteric, and the fetish for the home row made my hands sad. Vim is seen as an text editor only for programmers who can touch type and there seemed, to me at least, to be a air of elitism around it and some of its users. But as with all things, you should not judge an editor by its community. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if Losh’s post was better written than others I had read or I just found it at the right time, but I &lt;em&gt;got&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; what Vim could do for me. By focusing first and foremost on “you can keep your hands on the home row yay” I think a lot of Vim fans are missing an substantial audience. For mine, coming to it new, Vim’s best feature is its deep customisation. This is doubly true for users with specific physical needs. Almost every key can be made to do something else or many things else. Coupled with  minimal chording out of the box, Vim could well be what I’ve been looking for. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim reduces the reliance on chords by thinking of editing like writing sentences. For Losh, editing with Vim is like a language:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have &amp;quot;verbs&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;nouns&amp;quot;. For example: the &amp;quot;change&amp;quot; command (c) would be a verb and the &amp;quot;word&amp;quot; item (w) is a noun. You can combine them to form sentences. The wonderful part about this is that whenever you learn a new verb (like &amp;quot;delete&amp;quot; (d)) you can immediately apply it to all the nouns you know&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the sentence “delete four words” becomes &lt;code&gt;d4w&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. Want to change everything inside a set of parentheses? &lt;code&gt;ci(&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. Of course this is the very tip of the Titanic-sized iceberg of what Vim can do. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, if you&#x27;re writing fiction, as I am, you can get by without filling your head with key combos. You can get by with just: &lt;code&gt;d&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;elete, &lt;code&gt;y&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;ank (copy), &lt;code&gt;c&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;hange, and &lt;code&gt;p&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;ut (paste).  In this first week I’ve relied on these four commands (as well as some help from the beginner guides &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;therandymon.com&#x2F;woodnotes&#x2F;vim-for-writers&#x2F;vimforwriters.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;rc3.org&#x2F;2012&#x2F;05&#x2F;12&#x2F;the-grammar-of-vim&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and things have been relatively smooth. Besides, you use all these commands in &lt;strong&gt;normal&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; mode (think &lt;em&gt;editing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; mode). Actual writing happens in &lt;strong&gt;insert&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; mode and that  remains the basically same as any other editor. Fans of modal editors like Vim believe splitting writing and editing into two separate tasks increases focus. At the very least, eliminating the stop–start of editing in situ &lt;em&gt;should&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; reduce the stress on my hands. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it sounds like Vim replaces stretching your hand into painful positions with a lot more key presses. And while I’ve found that to be true in my testing so far, that’s before I learned about the leader key. Vim’s leader key work like iOS’s shift toggle BUT can be made to do anything vim can with two keys. Want to find–and–replace cat for dog and then indent only the lines without the word fleas? You can. And you can map it to simply &lt;code&gt;leader + c&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. Further, you can choose which key is the leader. I’ve set it as &lt;code&gt;space&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; so I can easily reach every other key to perform my custom mappings. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-now&quot;&gt;What now?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan now is to switch out the keyboards and attempt to use Vim full time for day–to–day writing, customising things when and if I need as I go. I’ll come back in a month or so with an update on whether my hands are better, worse, or the same, and if this has been an exercise in yak shaving. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;status&quot;&gt;Status&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cat: Sleeping&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing: Ongoing&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hands: Despondent &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/about/</link>
            <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/about/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi I&#x27;m Michael. I&#x27;m a writer and typo enthusiast from New South Wales, Australia.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite bad hands, I write about disability, mental health and politics. My words have appeared in &lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. My short fiction has appeared in the &lt;em&gt;Newcastle Short Story Award&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I&#x27;m currently working on my first novel.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-site&quot;&gt;About the site&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is built with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;zola&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posts are written with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;1writerapp.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;1writer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;notepad-plus-plus.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Notepad++&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
