<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Michael Buckley</title>
    <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Michael Buckley</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Quick Brown Foxes</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2024-08-18-fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2024-08-18-fox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My eyes aren&amp;rsquo;t what they used to be. A bog witch hasn&amp;rsquo;t turned them into&#xA;tiny owls&amp;ndash;they are still eyes. But they are becoming less good at &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Glasses may be in my future, but for now the issue is text. I can read&#xA;books or the newspaper (because I’m a thousand) as well as I ever could,&#xA;so it’s something specific to &lt;em&gt;screen&lt;/em&gt; text. I have tried the obvious&#xA;things to work around it; increasing font size and using dark mode where&#xA;possible. But both options come with their own problems and annoying edge&#xA;cases. It helped. A bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2024-05-23-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2024-05-23-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An announcement and an apology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last month I got married. Surprisingly, given who I am as a person I was&#xA;not anxious on the day, even when there was worry it would rain. I almost&#xA;burst into hot tears the moment I saw Ceil in their dress and then again&#xA;in the car, but I managed to keep it together for the ceremony. I was&#xA;completely calm saying those words in front of people. It was a amazing&#xA;day and even though it was overcast the gardens where we had ceremony were&#xA;stunning. If you follow me on social media you will have already been&#xA;bombarded with photos. And videos. Ciel has wonderfully documented the&#xA;whole thing on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@TaciturnMiss&#34;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;. Needless&#xA;to say but I’m saying it anyway, we are disgustingly happy and looking&#xA;forward to many, many adventures together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2024-02-07-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2024-02-07-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far this year has been taken up with planning for the upcoming wedding.&#xA;It’s a lovely thing to be busy with, however it has left little&#xA;brain–space for anything else. Writing—both &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; and this blog—have&#xA;taken the backseat. Which is fine. But I’m looking forward to getting back&#xA;into it now most things have settled into place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of work to be done on The Book: Copy–editing to do. Scenes&#xA;to add or rewrite. We’ve found a new character who is demanding to be&#xA;included. This written–during–pandemic book is taking up &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of the&#xA;post–pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Default Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2023-11-12-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2023-11-12-default/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bunch of tech-bloggers, which I’m very much not, have been posting their&#xA;default applications over the past week or so. I think there was a&#xA;podcast. Anyway, I heard about it in a post by &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubenerd.com/my-default-applications/&#34;&gt;rubenerd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And here’s mine. It’s not very interesting or esoteric, but at least it&#xA;keeps this site from looking dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;💾 Backups: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hanselman.com/blog/windows-8-step-0-turn-on-continuous-backups-via-file-history&#34;&gt;FileHistory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.synology.com/&#34;&gt;Synology NAS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;💰 Budgeting: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hledger.org/&#34;&gt;hledger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🖥 Desktop: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-au/&#34;&gt;Windows 10&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Debian XFCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;📝 Docs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org/&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;📫 Email: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thunderbird.net&#34;&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🖼 Images: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gimp.org/&#34;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://inkscape.org/&#34;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🎧 Music: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foobar2000.org/&#34;&gt;foobar2000&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mplayerhq.hu&#34;&gt;MPlayer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;💬 Podcasts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gpodder.github.io/&#34;&gt;gPodder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🍿 RSS: &lt;a href=&#34;https://netnewswire.com/&#34;&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;👨‍💻 Scripting: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bash_(Unix_shell)&#34;&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerShell&#34;&gt;PowerShell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autohotkey.com/&#34;&gt;ahk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🐚 Shell: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bash_(Unix_shell)&#34;&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/PowerShell&#34;&gt;PowerShell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;✏️ Text editor: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/&#34;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;📺 Video: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.videolan.org/&#34;&gt;VLC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;🕸 Web browser: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2023-10-01-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2023-10-01-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first half of the year (now 9 months) has been eaten up with more than&#xA;usual ill health, which culminated in a night time ride in an ambulance&#xA;and a overnight stay in hospital. Thankfully, things have started to level&#xA;out enough that I can concentrate on other things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We managed to get &lt;em&gt;Frances&lt;/em&gt; out to some folks a few months ago and&#xA;honestly I’m find the whole beta reading thing kinda frustrating. Not&#xA;because of the lovely people who decided to take it on. They are total&#xA;sweethearts. But because it turns out I’m a very impatient person; I both&#xA;want and dread feedback. Being extra  sick and having else to focus on&#xA;hasn’t helped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022-11-12-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022-11-12-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few weeks my part of the world has been submerged under&#xA;water. There’s been sandbagging and phones pinging warnings and evacuation&#xA;orders and helicopters going back and forth overhead. While our street&#xA;remained dry—they put in a flood wall after the last major flood in the&#xA;90s but it had been untested until now—the south side of the river wasn’t&#xA;as lucky and many homes are still under water and many others were&#xA;damaged. This has all been &lt;em&gt;not great&lt;/em&gt; for someone with an anxiety&#xA;disorder. And writing went out the window. Which was closed. Because of&#xA;the flood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022-10-12-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022-10-12-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing with another person can be a wonderful experience. Turns out&#xA;that’s even more true when you’re actually sitting beside your co-author.&#xA;And not just because they smell nice. I’m writing with my fiancé so that&#xA;last part isn’t weird.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far most of the work on our novel has been done over the internet, over&#xA;distance, and asynchronously—each working when our brains felt capable.&#xA;And that hasn’t been hard. The majority of our relationship happens over&#xA;long distance so we’re used to that. And adding writing to that wasn’t too&#xA;much of an ask.  Actually, I was unsure how working in the same room would&#xA;go. But sitting at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/agapanthusfran/status/1573859543570063361?s=46&amp;amp;t=UhzpzscVeTj-_yvdnctvFw&#34;&gt;same desk&lt;/a&gt; and being able to simply point at&#xA;things bought back the bounce and flow and &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; that I didn’t realise had&#xA;dissipated lately. So we’re excited again and the soft deadline of&#xA;Christmas (2022) seems accomplishable (it’s a word).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In The White Room With Black Curtains (By The Station)</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022-03-26-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2022-03-26-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about scene description while attempting to write&#xA;this book (yes that’s still happening). The question of how much scene&#xA;setting is necessary? How much is enough? What’s too much? Too little? How&#xA;many words are the difference between a scene that’s skeletal and one&#xA;that’s chonky?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;White Room Syndrome is the habit of creating a scenes that are so&#xA;under-described, so lacking detail that it could be taking place in a&#xA;featureless white-walled room in anywhere in the world. There is no sense&#xA;of place. And the characters are doing their stuff in an empty void as if&#xA;they’ve walked out of the picture like Daffy Duck in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6XvXsuSJ-1A&#34;&gt;Duck Amuck&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Obviously, scenes without specific, concrete locations are to be avoided&#xA;like the plague (assuming people actually avoid plagues anymore). But, as&#xA;a chronic under-writer, looking at thin scenes, it’s hard to not swing to&#xA;the other extreme when fleshing out the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words with Friend</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2021-08-12-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2021-08-12-friend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It started with a tweet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which became a discussion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then became a plan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We would write a book together&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you may know, this year my friend, Ciel, and I decided to attempt to&#xA;write a novel together. Neither of us have written a novel before. And I&#xA;haven’t co-written anything before. So we thought we should write some&#xA;kind of work log in case we forget how we did this thing (or anyone ever&#xA;asks about it). Here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Hands</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2021-02-18-morehands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2021-02-18-morehands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the experiment failed. Sort of. &lt;a href=&#34;2021-01-03.html&#34;&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt; I talked about changing to&#xA;vim in an effort to save my hands. Text entry of course ended up the same&#xA;and I could keep hitting my (paltry) word counts. But when editing, well,&#xA;there are too many commands to hold in my head, and most of my editing&#xA;time was spent consulting the cheat sheet on my desk. Editing became&#xA;wading through sticky molasses. Had I stuck with it perhaps this need&#xA;would lessen over time. Also, I kept falling back on using the mouse which&#xA;is very much frowned on in vim circles. BUT it turns out my hands&#xA;&lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; the relief that comes with stopping and moving to the electric&#xA;rodent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hands</title>
      <link>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2021-01-03-hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.michaelbuckleywriter.com/blog/2021-01-03-hands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two things that became obvious while attempting&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nanowrimo.org&#34;&gt;NanoWriMo&lt;/a&gt; in 2020. First, that procrastination&#xA;and global crisis are the most intimate of lovers and, second, my hands&#xA;are no longer capable of typing at a computer like they once were.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, I have Muscular Dystrophy, which is a muscle&#xA;weakening condition. What this means is, among myriad other things,  my&#xA;hands have been slowly worsening over time. Think of how your hands look&#xA;when holding a gamepad, now take the pad away and imagine you can’t&#xA;straighten your fingers out. Yep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
